Prathmesh Temkar

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

prathmesh.temkar@gmail.com

+91-9987950575

Mumbai,India O



linkedin.com/in/prathmesh-temkar in



SUMMARY

Passionate front-end web developer with experience to build all aspects of the user experience and user interface for clientfacing landing pages. Passionate about usability and possess working knowledge of Adobe Photoshop & corelDraw, Currently learning Node.js, Next.js.

SKILLS AND TECHNOLOGIES

- · HTML, CSS, Javascript
- · React.js, REST API
- TypeScript
- Azure sdk
- Next is
- . HTTP, Git
- · Bootstrap, Material-UI
- Python
- NPM
- Webpack
- Redux

EXPERIENCE

Associate - Front-end developer (Reactis)

Tata Consultancy Services Nov 2020 - Present

- Developed Single Page Application using React and Azure SDK to save cloud costs.
- Developed Proficency to work on Large incoming data from API's.
- Acuired Knowdgle on using AzureSDK in ReactJS.
- Developed an Dashboard App using react-chartis-2, D3.js.

Associate - Network Engineer Support

Tata Consultancy Services Jul 2019 - Oct 2020

- Working on multiple technologies including FTTP,FTTN/B, FTTC (Fibre to the premise, Node, Building or Curb).
- Successfully creating logical Network trails for all technologies and also completing the Line and Port configurations on automation failures. Helping onsite technicians with all the line, port and general issues.

Specialist

Sterling Infosystems, Inc. Mar 2018 - Jun 2019

- Providing Employee verifications as per the Client's Preference. Strong decision making skills to determine if the candidate references recieved are cleared or not.
- Helping Clients with understanding if any issue or clarifications required within any references. Closing files with highest accuracy within the provided SLA.

PROJECTS

FELLOWSHIP IN SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT (Frontend) - CRIO.DO Developer 2022

QKart (Ecommerce) - https://qkart-pratham.netlify.app/

- Implemented the core logic for authentication, shopping cart and checkout.
- Improved UI by adding responsive design elements for uniform experience across different devices.
- Utilized REST APIs to dynamically load and render data served by the backend server.

XBoard(Newsfeed) - https://prathmesh-xboard.netlify.app/

- Built XBoard using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript and JQuery from scratch.
- Used Accordions and Image Carousel to improve UI.
- Fetched news content from flipboard's RSS feed using REST API.

QTrip(Travel) - https://pratham-qtrip-frontend.netlify.app/

- Created web pages using HTML and CSS and made them dynamic using JavaScript.
- Improved UX with multi-select filters, image carousels Used JQuery to facilitate the reservation form submission.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science - Computer Science University of Mumbai 2014 - 2017

CERTIFICATION

React JS Developer Bootcamp LearnCodeOnline.in

Python Data Analytics Udemy

Python 3 LearnCodeOnline.in